SEDAT SERCAN CENGIZ



+90 534 254 1785 sercancng@gmail.com Kecioren / ANKARA

PROFILE

Baskent Universities computer engineering department student, who strong in human relations, programmed and planned in his studies and sees software development as an entertainment rather than seeing it as a job. With more than 3 years of experience in Java and Android application development, he is skilled in this field and prone to teamwork. Developing their own projects at every opportunity. He has 6 months of research and development experience in machine learning and artificial intelligence. I have been working on web-based application development, designing websites and at the Front-End for a year. He is currently engaged in research and development activities on the autonomous drone movement in the field of artificial intelligence.

EXPERIENCE

Intern Engineer, Turkish Aerospace Industries, Ankara - 2019 - Current Designing and developing GUI for MMU project.

Intern, HAVELSAN A.S, Ankara - 2019

Preparing XML for working in TeamCity program, XML Builder preparation to make it easier to prepare XML from available data, Designing and developing a GUI for the prepared XML Builder, Studies on Docker and AWX.

Intern Engineer, Turkish Aerospace Industries, Ankara - 2018 - 2019

Preparation of license management system and preparation of a website suitable for this system, Studies on time synchronization between servers.

Intern, ATAR Labs Bilisim A.S, Ankara - 2018

Testing the previously prepared Scripts on the system, Preparing new scripts to work on ATAR, Preparation of job tracking system between jobs & users.

EDUCATION

Baskent University, Ankara - 2015 - Current

GPA: 3.49 / 4.00

Alparslan Anatolian High School, Ankara - 2011 - 2015

SKILLS

C, C++, C#, Java, Kotlin, Python, Perl, SQL, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

English (Upper-Intermediate), Turkish (Native Language) PROJECTS

PROJECTS

Android

- MarketApp: Showing the products in the system to the user, listing similar products and adding selected products to the basket
- **UlasBana**: Visual design, interface development, earning points and saving the score in the database
- **Cliya**: Development of the system that enables doctors to enter the diseases database, informing the user if there is an epidemic in the region where it is located
- Where Is My Gift: A mobile game like Flappy Bird
- A social media app study like Onedio tests
- Firebase application that encrypts end-to-end using AES for internal communications
- Information application about music groups

Java

- Animal information and tracking system for pet-shops
- · Game bot systems prepared with Selenium

Kotlin

• Designing and developing a GUI to make it easier to prepare XML

C#

- Stack of Shape: Mobile game prepared with Unity 3D
- Tap Picture: Mobile game prepared with Unity 3D
- Simulation environment for drone artificial intelligence with Unity 3D

DEGREE, SCHOLARSHIP AND CERTIFICATES

- OSYM 50% Education Scholarship
- METU Hackaton 2019, Participant
- Iste Baskent 2018, Participant
- E-GameShow Redbull-GboxVR 2017, Organization Team
- Iste Baskent 2017, Organization Team

REFERENCES

- Emre SÜMER, Baskent University, Deputy Head of Computer Engineering Department, 0312 246 6666 / 1305
- Mehmet Bugra BILMEZ, Kale Yazılım, Software Specialist, 0 (533) 542 93 07
- Serkan KUCUK, Innova Bilisim Cozumleri A.S, Application Development Consultant, 0 (533) 706 66 89
- Sena Nur GOREN, TUBITAK Bilgem Iltaren, Researcher, 0 (538) 611 74 85
- Ahmet DEDE, HAVELSAN, DevOps Engineer, 0 (506) 332 84 43